{
  "questions" : [ {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "A long double can be used if range of a double is not enough to accommodate a real number.",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "True", "False" ],
    "answers" : [ "True" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "True, we can use long double; if double range is not enough. double = 8 bytes. long double = 10 bytes."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "A float is 4 bytes wide, whereas a double is 8 bytes wide.",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "True", "False" ],
    "answers" : [ "True" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "True, float = 4 bytes. double = 8 bytes."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "If the definition of the external variable occurs in the source file before its use in a particular function, then there is no need for an extern declaration in the function.",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "True", "False" ],
    "answers" : [ "True" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "True, When a function is declared inside the source file, that function(local function) get a priority than the extern function. So there is no need to declare a function as extern inside the same source file."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Size of short integer and long integer can be verified using the sizeof() operator.",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "True", "False" ],
    "answers" : [ "True" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "True, we can find the size of short integer and long integer using the sizeof() operator. Example: \n#include<stdio.h>\nint main()\n{\n    short int i = 10;\n    long int j = 10;\n    printf(\"short int is %d bytes.,\\nlong int is %d bytes.\",\n            sizeof(i),sizeof(j));\n    return 0;\n}\n Output: short int is 2 bytes. long int is 4 bytes."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Range of double is -1.7e-38 to 1.7e+38 (in 16 bit platform - Turbo C under DOS)",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "True", "False" ],
    "answers" : [ "False" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "False, The range of double is -1.7e+308 to 1.7e+308."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Size of short integer and long integer would vary from one platform to another.",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "True", "False" ],
    "answers" : [ "True" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "True, Depending on the operating system/compiler/system architecture you are working on, the range of data types can vary."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Range of float id -2.25e+308 to 2.25e+308",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "True", "False" ],
    "answers" : [ "False" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "False, The range of float is -3.4e+38 to 3.4e+38."
  },
{
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Is there any difference in the following declarations? int myfun(int arr[]); int myfun(arr[20]);",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "Yes", "No" ],
    "answers" : [ "Yes" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "Yes, we have to specify the data type of the parameter when declaring a function."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Suppose a program is divided into three files f1, f2 and f3, and a variable is defined in the file f1 but used in files f2 and f3. In such a case would we need the extern declaration for the variables in the files f2 and f3?",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "Yes", "No" ],
    "answers" : [ "Yes" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Global variable are available to all functions. Does there exist a mechanism by way of which it available to some and not to others.",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "Yes", "No" ],
    "answers" : [ "No" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "The only way this can be achieved is to define the variable locally in main() instead of defining it globally and then passing it to the functions which need it."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Is it true that a global variable may have several declarations, but only one definition?",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "Yes", "No" ],
    "answers" : [ "Yes" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "Yes, In all the global variable declarations, you need to use the keyword extern."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Is it true that a function may have several declarations, but only one definition?",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "Yes", "No" ],
    "answers" : [ "Yes" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "Yes, but the function declarations must be identical. Example: #include<stdio.h>\n\nvoid Display();\nvoid Display();\nvoid Display();\n\nvoid Display()\n{\n   printf(\"Weclome to IndiaBIX.com..!\");\n}\n\nint main()\n{\n    Display();\n    return 0;\n}\n\n//Output:\nWeclome to IndiaBIX.com..!"
  }  ],
  "currentIndex" : 0,
  "testMillis" : 0,
  "testTime" : false,
  "remainingTimeInitialized" : false,
  "remainingTestMillis" : 0,
  "ref" : "https://www.indiabix.com/c-programming/declarations-and-initializations/005001"
}